Guide to the Donald M. Goldstein Collection, 1886-2005 UA.90.F78
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Photographs, XIII.
  - Non World War II, 1.
    - Vietnam War
      - Published Images, 1962 - 1995 (Box Photo 4, Folder 1-5)
        - An air hero of two wars – Korea and Vietnam – Col. James Jabra prepares a postflight report documenting his fighter-bombing mission over Vietnam on July 18, 1966., 226.
        - A reconnaissance photograph shows three Russian-built MiG-17s behind protective revetments at Phuc Yen field, 20 miles northwest of Hanoi., 227.
          U.S. pilots were frustrated that they were not permitted to attack the airfields.
        - A North Vietnamese MiG-17 disintegrates under 20mm cannon fire from an F-105D of the 34th Tactical Fighter Squadron on August 13, 1966., 228.
        - Gregory "Pappy" Boyington, top-scoring Marine ace of Pacific War fame, poses for a photograph with the men of his old squadron., 229.
        - Plumes from the explosions of 750-pound bombs dropped by F-105 Thunderchiefs blossom skyward from the Xuan Mai Army Barracks and Supply Center during an attack on April 19, 1967., 230.
        - F-105 Thunderchief pilots delivered their ordnance onto Hanoi's railyard car repair and storage facility, 2-1/4 miles northeast of the city center during May 1967., 231.
        - Col. Robin Olds, a fighter pilot whose career extended back to the Second World War, examines ordnance mounted under the wing of his F-4C prior to a mission over Vietnam in 1967., 232.
          This aircraft is loaded for an air-to-ground mission. Often, the F-4s would load up with air-to-air missiles to fly MiG cover for the air-to-ground missions.
        - Col. Jack M. Broughton Deputy Commander of the 355th Tactical Fighter Squadron, congratulates F-105 ("Thud") pilot Maj. William J. Bailey, who has just returned form his 100th mission over Vietnam., 233.
          Bailey donned a portion of his World War II flight gear to mark the occasion.
        - Maj. Ralph L. Kuster of the 13th Tactical Fighter Squadron races toward an enemy MiG-17 at 200 knots closure speed during a wild dogfight over North Vietnam on June 3, 1967., 234.
        - An F-100 cuts loose a salvo of folding-fin rockets into a Vietcong position in South Vietnam during July 1967., 235.
        - North Vietnamese military personnel and civilians savor the moment as they parade a recently shot down American aviator into captivity., 236.
        - Manacled together, two American fliers are put on display before angry, jeering North Vietnamese during July 1967, prior to their delivery to authorities for interrogation., 237.
          Supported by his compatriot, the man at right appears dazed and injured.
        - His broken right arm and multiple burns eliciting no sympathy from the crowds, Lt. David C, Rehman is paraded before a hostile North Vietnamese public., 238.
        - American prisoner of war Navy Lt. Paul Galanti provides a very much coached and coerced film interview., 239.
        - Empty shell casings from the 8-inch guns of Newport News (CA-128) litter the heavy cruiser's forecastle during bombardment in support of I Corps Marines in the DMZ during the latter months of 1967., 240.
        - On board the aircraft carrier Canberra (CAG-2), sailors in the plotting room work out a firing solution for a target on the Vietnamese shore., 241.
        - Smoke and flame belch from the 6-inch guns of Galveston (CLG-3) as six more shells hurtle toward a target in Vietnam., 242.
        - Welcome to Vietnam., 243.
          Newly arrived troops disembark from an aircraft at Cam Ranh Bay's 14th Aerial Port.
        - Arrivals from Tan Son Nhut Air Base ride by bus to the 90th Replacement Battalion at Long Binh Post., 244.
        - Troops arrive from their bus ride at the 90th Replacement Battalion reception station., 245.
        - Processing begins at Long Binh with a stack of forms., 246.
        - Men of the 1st Cavalry Division (Airmobile) draw equipment from the Central Issue Facility of the 266 Supply and Service Battalion at Long Binh., 247.
        - A Navy Seabee muscles a load of concrete during construction at Chu Lai., 248.
        - Cam Ranh Bay's South Beach, seen here in a view looking north in June 1966., 249.
        - A panorama of the gasoline tank farm facility at Cam Ranh Bay., 250.
          When American first joined the war, there were almost no runways in the region that could support American aircraft. A massive building effort was necessary.
        - The deep water port and property disposal operation at Da Nang., 251.
        - Military Police escort travelers through the village of An Phu., 252.
        - A convoy moves along the road leading to Duc Pho from Chu Lai., 253.
        - An aerial view of Fire Support Base Sedgwick of the 25th Infantry Division located near Cu Chi, seen on August 11, 1969., 254.
        - Land clearing operations at Fire Base Eunice., 255.
        - Sand-bagged buildings at Fire Support Base Black Hawk., 256.
          Note the barbed wire obstruction in the distance.
        - View of Fire Base Jerre showing dugouts and tents used as living quarters in December 1969., 257.
        - The open-air briefing "room" at Fire Base Sabre., 258.
        - Thomas Brides of the 119th Light Infantry prepares a meal for the men of his unit at Fire Support Base Eagle., 259.
          Admiring his handiwork are (left to right) SP4 Larry Simple and SP4 Willie Rose.
        - Sgt. Ed Densen of the 27th Infantry, 25th Infantry Division, opens a pack of C-ration cocoa at the end of the day's work during a search-and-clear operation near Fire Support Base Kien on August 10, 1970., 260.
        - SSgt. William George hefts a turkey drumstick onto the plate of SP4 Roy Wiley of the 1st Cavalry Division (Airmobile) during a meal on Thanksgiving 1967., 261.
          Wiley's equipment was typical of the "grunt": "steel pot" helmet with camouflage cover, M-16 rifle, load-bearing equipment, and protective mask.
        - An ARVN mess cook prepares a batch of small fish for conversion into nuoc mam sauce, a standard element of the Vietnamese diet., 262.
        - Vietnamese support troops of the 50th Political Warfare Battalion enjoy their noonday meal in their battalion's newly constructed dining hall in Saigon., 263.
        - GOOD MORNING VIETNAM!!, 264.
          SSgt. Richard A. Van Dorn, Radio Production Chief of Da Nang Armed Forces Radio, "spins the wax" during a musical program on February 1, 1968.
        - Letters from home cheer the men during mail call at Landing Zone Stud, a forward base of the 1st Cavalry Division (Airmobile), on March 30, 1968., 265.
        - A chaplain of the 82d Airborne Division tends his flock at Camp Eagle during April 1968., 266.
        - Men of the 101st Airborne Division take time out from Operation Van Buren in late January 1966 for religious services in the field., 267.
        - At Ben Cat, about 50 miles north of Saigon, a corpsman of the 1st Medical Battalion administers a transfusion to a wounded man., 268.
        - AUH-1D takes off to airlift an injured member of the 101st Airborne Division near the DMZ., 269.
        - The 93d Evacuation Hospital at Long Binh in the fall of 1967., 270.
        - Interior of the Tuy Hoa evacuation hospital on July 15, 1967., 271.
        - Capt. Bernice Scott and Lt. David Van Voorhis of the Army Nurse Corps remove field bandages from a seriously wounded soldier sent to the 2d Surgical Hospital for treatment., 272.
        - Christmas in Vietnam, red Cross aides Joyce MacCaonnackie and Khaki Barden join Lt. Daniel L. Baldwin of the 9th Infantry Division in serving Christmas dinner for troops on the field on December 13, 1967., 273.
        - Armed Forces Radio disk jockey Chris Noel performs on camera for the troops during a Christmas Special in 1967., 274.
        - Sgt. Craig Anderson of the 7th Marines savors a Christmas card received from home on December 19, 1969., 275.
        - Bob Hope, a Christmas institution for three generations of American Servicemen overseas, teams up with the Golddiggers at Long Binh during Christmas 1968., 276.
        - Members of the 101st Airborne Division enjoy the antics of Hope and company at Camp Eagle on the day before Christmas Eve 1970., 277.
        - Seated on their duffle bags, 7th Cavalry soldiers wait at Vung Tau Airfield for transportation to the R&R Center at that facility., 278.
        - Soldiers relax on Vung Tau Beach at the R&R Center where there appears to be only one problem – no women!, 279.
        - A drug raid in Da Nang by Vietnamese civilian authorities nets a room full of drug paraphernalia, opium, and marijuana., 280.
        - Buddhist family shrines set up in the streets of Hué., 281.
        - Film and office equipment in the rear of the U.S. information Service Building in Hué, destroyed by Buddhist demonstrators on May 26, 1966., 282.
        - A group of marchers hold aloft pr-American signs in English., 283.
        - Phu Nom Signal Communications Site located in the Cholon section of Saigon., 284.
        - In the Tan Son Nhut area north of Saigon, personnel at the Combined Document Exploitation Center translate copies of captured enemy documents., 285.
        - American soldiers packing propaganda leaflets into "bombs," which will be dropped in strategic areas of North Vietnam., 286.
        - Using a microphone, a member of the 403d ARVN Political Warfare Company speaks to villagers of Ap Trung, 7 miles northwest of My Tho, about what they can do to keep Highway 4 secure., 287.
        - An ABC television news crew unloads their equipment at "The Rock Pile" (Khe Sanh) on October 29, 1967., 288.
        - At Khe Sanh, the 101st Airborne Cavalry set up the "Khe Sanh Saloon," a briefing tent and reading room for the news correspondence., 289.
        - PFC Stephen Gaye of the 11th Light Infantry Brigade's S-4 Section conducts English classes for Vietnamese children at Duc Pho during mid-January 1968., 290.
        - Children at the Holy Cross Church School in Bac Hai hamlet clutch candy and C.A.R.E. school packets during a Tet New Year's party hosted by the 199th Light Infantry Brigade on January 28, 1968., 291.
        - A member of the 39th Infantry, 9th Infantry Division, carries a sick Vietnamese woman through a muddy rice field to a central medical staging area., 292.
        - ARVN troops advance against communist positions in Saigon during the 1968 Tet Offensive while large sections of the city burn, set afire by Vietcong insurgents., 293.
        - Nineteen Vietcong infiltrated the U.S. embassy grounds in Saigon after blasting this hole in the wall surrounding the compound., 294.
        - Navy corpsmen wearing flak jackets evacuate an American soldier wounded during the attack on the U.S. embassy on January 31, 1968., 295.
        - The burned-out wreck of a C-47 aircraft lies on the apron at Tan Son Nhut Air Base, A victim of rocket and mortar fire., 296.
        - Soldiers move up an M-113 armored personnel carrier and an M-48A3 tank in Saigon during the height of the Tet Offensive., 297.
        - A member of the 1st Battalion, 18th Infantry Division, pauses at a memorial during a search for Vietcong forces in Saigon's French military cemetery during February 1, 1968., 298.
        - Feb. 1, 1968., 299.
          Members of the 119th Light Infantry Brigade established a refugee camp at Long Binh for Vietnamese driven from their home during the Tet Offensive.
        - February 2, 1968., 300.
          An armored personnel carrier passes buildings that American forces damaged when they rooted the Vietcong from their hiding places in Bien Hoa.
        - Clad in hospital pajamas and flak jacket, patient SP4 Norm W. Singleton checks a Vietnamese employee's identification card at the entrance to the 3d Field Hospital during 1968., 301.
          Note that he carries an M-4 rifle.
        - Hué during the Tet Offensive. Supported by tanks, Marines move to clear buildings in street fighting near Hué University on February 3, 1968., 302.
        - Leathernecks of B Company, 1st battalion, 1st Marines, aid trapped fellow Marines while under heavy machine-gun fire during fighting in Hué., 303.
        - February 4, 1968., 304.
          Gunnery Sgt. F. A. Thomas of the 5th Marines finds a bit of GI humor in a toy car amidst heavy fighting during the battle for Hué.
        - Cpl. Gary D. Keller of the 1st Marine Division fires his M-60 machine gun through a bathroom window on February 6., 305.
        - 5th Marine PFC A.D. Crum of New Brighton, Pennsylvania, receives a field dressing from Navy Corpsman D.R. Howe on February 6., 306.
        - A Marine from A Company, 1st Battalion, 1st Marine, moves out under heavy machine-gun fire in Hué during intense street fighting on February 9., 307.
        - A portion of Hué's destroyed marketplace, seen on February 14, 1968., 308.
        - Men of the 2d Battalion, 5th Marines, relax in front of a bullet-scarred building and light up cigarettes during a lull in the battle for Hué on February 18, 1968., 309.
        - A weary Marine collapses in a heap on the front of his Ontos armored vehicle during a lull in the fighting in Hué on February 23, 1968., 310.
          The Ontos carried four 106mm recoilless rifles.
        - Seen on February 28, a bridge lies collapsed in the Perfume River in Hué, blown up by North Vietnamese sappers earlier in the offensive., 311.
        - Walter Cronkite of CBS News interviews a Vietnamese professor of the University of Hué on February 20, 1968., 312.
        - Marines blast away with a 105mm howitzer at the North Vietnamese forces surrounding Khe Sanh in January 1968., 313.
        - An interior view of one of the many defensive fighting trenches held by Marines at Khe Sanh., 314.
        - A forward observer at Khe Sanh looks for signs of the enemy activity in the distance., 315.
        - MSgt. Charles Wunderlich of the 82d Airborne Division's 3d Brigade reads a newspaper on February 14, 1968, during his unit's flight to Vietnam., 316.
        - Newly arrived troops of the 505th Infantry, 82d Airborne Division, stand watch during the search of a Vietnamese house near the divisional base camp on February 25, 1968., 317.
        - Burdened with dufflebags and equipment, soldiers of the 82d Airborne Division exit the rear of a C-141 transport at Chu Lai Marine Corps Air Station in mid-February 1968., 318.
        - Crewmen on board an Essex-class aircraft carrier prepare a Ch-47B Chinook of the 271st Aviation Company for its flight into Vietnam on February 25, 1968., 319.
          The helicopter has been pulled off the elevator and forward on the flight deck where the rotors will be installed. Note the cover catapult on the deck.
        - Maj. John P. Obermire leads the 271st Aviation Company out of their LCS landing craft onto the beach at Vung Tau., 320.
        - Clark Clifford, who on March 1, 1968, replaced Robert McNamara as secretary of Defense. (see photo 8-47), 321.
        - General Creighton W. Abrams, who replaced Westmoreland as commander, MACV., 322.
        - Saigon firemen pick up body of a dead Vietcong soldier following an attack on that city during May 6, 1968., 323.
        - From atop a tank located on the southwest perimeter of Tan Son Nhut Air Base on May 7, soldiers fire a .50-caliber machine gun into a Vietcong position inside the Old French Cemetery., 324.
        - Vietnamese Air Force troops lift a wounded comrade into a trench near the center of the Old French Cemetery during the heavy fighting off Plantation Road on May 7., 325.
        - Bodies of three enemy soldiers litter the street just off Plantation Road during the battle that raged in and around the Old French Cemetery., 326.
        - Fires set by Vietcong snappers burn out of control on the Newport side of the Tu Duc Bridge in Saigon during May 8, 1968., 327.
        - An M-48 tank of the 25th Infantry Division backs into blocking force position on a Saigon street during the North Vietnamese and Vietcong attack on the city on May 8., 328.
        - Spanning the Saigon River, the "Y" Bridge linked the suburbs of Cholon and Gia Dinh province with Saigon., 329.
        - Members of the 47th Infantry proudly display a flag captured during a house-to-house search of the areas south of the Kinh Doi Canal and the "Y" Bridge during final mopping-up operations outside Saigon on May 13, 1968., 330.
        - C-123 aircraft of the 12th Air Commando Squadron flying in formation spray defoliant chemicals on a jungle area east of Saigon on June 7, 1968., 331.
        - Jungle areas following defoliation operations., 332.
        - The nuclear-powered aircraft carrier Enterprise (CVA (N)-65) steams in the waters off Indochina., 333.
        - PFC Tracy Gray rams an artillery round into the tube of a 105mm howitzer, assisted by gunner PFC John L. K. Alston during 9th Infantry Division operations in the My Cong River complex in June 1968., 334.
        - Troops of the 131st Engineering Company unload their cargo from a landing craft onto the beach at Vung Tau on September 21, 1968., 335.
          Mormacaltair, a Military Sea Transport Contract Freighter, stand by offshore in the distance.
        - The political changing of the guard. President-elect Richard M. Nixon's incoming secretary of Defense, Melvin R. Laird, confers with his outgoing counterpart, Clark M. Clifford, on December 13, 1968., 336.
          The portrait in the background is that of former secretary James V. Forrestal.
        - Lt. Col. Cecil G. Foster, commander of the 390th Tactical Fighter Squadron, counts his blessings as he stands up through a hole in the win fog his F-4 Phantom damaged by antiaircraft fire during a mission in August 1968., 337.
        - Two A-1 Skyraiders of the 6th Special Operations Squadron fly protective cover for an HH-3E helicopter of the 37th Aerospace Rescue and Recovery Squadron., 338.
        - Bandaged and disconsolate, U.S. Air Force Lt. Col. J.L. Hughes is escorted through a park in Hanoi in May 1969., 339.
        - Veterans of two previous wars, the battleship New Jersey (BB-62) fires its main battery into a North Vietnamese position near the Vietnamese coast during 1969., 340.
        - Veterans of two previous wars, the battleship New Jersey (BB-62) fires its main battery into a North Vietnamese coast during 1969., 340.
        - Monitors of the 2d Brigade, Mobile Riverine Force, 9th Infantry Division patrol the Song Ba Lai River on April 14, 1968., 341.
        - A Riverine Force crewman trains his M-60 machine gun at a suspicious object on shore while traveling at high speed up the Song My Tho River near Dong Tam on 29 January 1969., 342.
        - Aerial view of the barracks ship Benewah., 343.
          Note its brood of monitors and landing craft nested alongside.
        - On the fantail of Benewah (APB-35) sailors man a 40mm quadruple mount while on patrol in the Glad Due area during April 16, 1968., 344.
          Note the empty shell casings visible in the gun tub at lower left.
        - A SEAL team's outboard-motor assault boat speeds down a branch of the Mekong River with its squad of commandos., 345.
        - SEAL Team Leader Lt. (j.g.) Robert Kerrey, later a U.S. senator, was awarded the Medal of Honor for action against Vietcong forces in South Vietnam., 346.
          Kerrey's team attempted the capture of an enemy political cadre located on an island near Nha Trang.
        - A combat team of the 4th Infantry Detachment (War Dog Provisional) sets out on the trail of a fleeing enemy on February 18, 1969., 347.
        - In response to a Vietcong attack on Long Binh Post, members of the 1stt Squadron, 11th Armored Cavalry Regiment, move out in their M-113 armored personnel carrier to pursue the Vietcong, after taking a short break in a Vietnamese a short break in a Vietnamese cemetery during February 23, 1969., 348.
        - PFC Charles W. Lowery of the 52d Artillery Group arms a 155mm projectile with a fuse at this unit base in Pleiku on March 6, 1969., 349.
        - Secretary of Defense Melvin Laird greets a squad of Marines of the 1st Marine Division following his arrival in Da Nang during his visit to the I Corps area on March 9, 1969., 350.
        - Secretary of State William P. Rogers listens while members of the 3d Reconnaissance Battalion, 3d Marine Division, explain the mission of reconnaissance patrols in the north sector of I Corps., 351.
        - Members of the 77th Artillery, 25th Infantry Division, direct their 105mm howitzer fire from Fire Support Base Sedgwick in support of an Infantry operation during May 2, 1969., 352.
        - South Vietnamese General Cao Van Vein presents the Vietnamese Cross of Gallantry and the civil Action Honor Medal to Maj. Gen. Harris W. Hollis, former commanding general of the 9th Infantry Division at Dong Tam on July 5, 1969. Elements of the 9th Division took part in a stand-down and redeployment during July., 353.
        - An American color guard lowers and folds the flag at Fire Base Danger as part of the stand-down of the 4th Battalion, 39th Infantry Division., 354.
        - Dong Team during the 9th Division's stand-down., 355.
          A truck of the division's 2d Brigade carrying communications equipment form the Ben Tre Base Camp enters the town, preparing for the unit's withdrawal.
        - July 13, 1969., 356.
          A CH-47 Chinook helicopter takes off from Dong Tam, bound for Bien Hoa Air Base, while participating in the withdrawal of the 9th Division from Vietnam.
        - With high hopes for an American "Generation of Peace," President Nixon greets U.S. ground forces during his trip to the Far East on July 30, 1969., 357.
        - By October 1969, many units were in the midst of the much-welcomed redeployment., 358.
          Troops of the 1st Cavalry Division (Airmobile) board an aircraft at Bien Hoa Air Base.
        - Fronted by helmets, rifles, and boots symbolic of fallen comrades, a brigade chaplain of the 82d Airborne leads a ceremony of remembrance at Phu Lai Veterans day, November 11, 1969., 359.
        - SSgt. James Craig of the 2d Squadron, 11th Cavalry, gingerly inspects a 22-pound Chinese mine during clearing operations near Quan Loi on December 26, 1969., 360.
          Photo number: 8-72
        - The mine-clearing team returns cautiously to Camp Eunice, 83 miles northwest of Saigon., 361.
          Photo number: 8-73
        - Averell Harriman, ambassador-at-large and head of the American delegation to preliminary talks on Vietnam, briefs the press in Paris, France, before the 1968 presidential election., 362.
        - Abbie Hoffman talking to University of Pittsburgh students (1962)., 363.
        - Students protest at the University of Pittsburgh (1962)., 364.
        - Service for Kent State students being held in front of the University of Pittsburgh (1962)., 365.
        - Ambassador David Bruce, chief U.S. negotiator at the Paris Peace Talks, greets South Vietnam's president, Nguyen Van Thieu., 366.
          U.S. Ambassador to Saigon, Ellsworth Bunker, stands behind.
        - Henry Kissinger (left) and Hanoi's senior representative Le Duc Tho (right) engage in animated conversation during a break in the peace talks at a villa in the Paris suburbs on November 23, 1972., 367.
          The two men had met for the first time on February 20, 1970, at a clandestine meeting in Paris.
        - Vietnamese Air Force students work on the rotor of a UH-1D helicopter during a course on helicopter maintenance at Fort Eustis Virginia in 1970., 368.
        - Richard G. Scalf and Thomas R. Parrott, both medics with the 1st Battalion, 22d Infantry, take time for a game of chess at Fire Support Base Louis., 369.